escapethecity.org 2013-05-28

# Escape the City

Escape the City (www.escapethecity.org) [hereafter known as ‘Escape the City’] is founded on the principle of helping people discover new career opportunities. We know that you care about how your personal information is used and shared, and we take your privacy very seriously. By visiting this website, you are accepting the practices outlined in this policy.

This Privacy Policy covers the treatment of personal information that Escape the City gathers when you are on this website and when you use this website’s services. This policy does not apply to the practices of third parties that Escape the City does not own or control, or to individuals that Escape the City does not employ or manage.

If you have questions or concerns regarding this privacy statement, please contact us: [team@escapethecity.org](mailto:team@escapethecity.org)

### Information Collected by Escape the City

We only collect personal information that is relevant to the purpose of our website. This information allows us to provide you with a customized and efficient experience. We collect the following types of information from our Escape the City users:

### Information You Provide to Us:

  1. We receive and store any information you enter on our website or provide to us in any other way. You can choose not to provide us with certain information, but then you may not be able to take advantage of many of our special features.
  2. **Registration:** In order for you to use Escape the City’s user profile services you must complete a registration form. As part of this registration form, we require select personal information. 
  3. **User Profile:** To allow you to express yourself beyond just the information collected during registration, we enable you to provide additional information, such as name, location, ‘escape introduction’, your past experience and your future aspirations. In addition, you may choose to include photos of yourself in your profile. As indicated below, in the section titled "Sharing Your Information", you can control how your information is displayed and used. 
  4. **Profile Elements:** We also save comments posted by users, links between user accounts (‘Supporter’ / ‘Supporting’) and links between user and organisation accounts (‘Follower’ / ‘Following’). 
  5. **Automatic Information:**
    1. We receive and store certain types of information whenever you interact with us. Escape the City and its authorized agents automatically receive and record certain "traffic data" on their server logs from your browser including your IP address, Escape the City cookie information, and the page you requested. Escape the City uses this traffic data to help diagnose problems with its servers, analyze trends and administer the website.
    2. Escape the City may collect and, on any page, display the total counts that page has been viewed. This includes User Profile pages.
    3. Many companies offer programs that help you to visit websites anonymously. While Escape the City will not be able to provide you with a personalized experience if we cannot recognize you, we want you to be aware that you can access the site without being logged in.
    4. Non-personal information: Individual identification numbers, known as an “IP addresses”, of the computers used by visitors to the site. IP addresses are automatically logged by Escape the City web servers. They are used, together with further information about visits to the site, to note a visitor's interest in the site and for statistical purposes. They do not allow us to identify the visitor unless he or she chooses to submit personal information to the site.
    5. Escape the City uses personal information collected through the site to authenticate users, to provide services through the site, to tailor and improve those services and to administer our member relationships.
    6. Escape the City may also use contact details collected through the site to send members [updates, newsletters or other communications] regarding escapethecity.org and the services available through the site. A member can choose not to receive these communications at any time.

We use the information you provide to personalise your online experience and to deliver the content most suited to your needs. We only use your personal information to respond to your requests and to provide you with information about what we do, unless we obtain your permission to use your information for something else. You can request to be removed from e-mails or other communications generated as a result of information provided via this site at any time.

### E-mail Communications

Escape the City is very concerned about your privacy and we will never provide your email address to a third party without your explicit permission, as detailed in the "Sharing Your Information" section below. Escape the City may send out e-mails with Escape the City-related news, products, offers, surveys or promotions. You may also receive notification e-mails from Escape the City, which inform you of actions (e.g. new supporters, comments) that have been performed on the site. If you do not want to receive e-mail from us, please visit the Notifications section of your User Profile and/or follow the instructions contained in the unwanted e-mail message. However, please note that in all cases you will continue to receive all system e-mails (e.g. those regarding forgotten user passwords) and legal notices (e.g. updates to our policies) from us.

### Cookies

On some areas of our site, we may use cookies, web beacons, server logs, and other technologies to collect aggregated, non-personal information. Cookies are small files which save information to enable your preferences when browsing a Web site to be remembered. They do not cause any damage to your computer or computer files and you are not obliged to accept the cookies which are used within the site.

Cookies are alphanumeric identifiers that we transfer to your computer's hard drive through your Web browser to enable our systems to recognize your browser and tell us how and when pages in our website are visited and by how many people. Escape the City cookies do not collect personal information, and we do not combine information collected through cookies with other personal information to tell us who you are or what your screen name or e-mail address is.

The "help" portion of the toolbar on the majority of browsers will direct you on how to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, how to command the browser to tell you when you receive a new cookie, or how to fully disable cookies. We recommend that you leave the cookies activated because cookies allow you to use some of Escape the City’'s coolest features. Some of our business partners, like our advertisers, may use cookies on our website. We have no access to, or control over, these cookies.

### Sharing Your Information

Because Escape the City enables people to discover new opportunities, information about the people who use Escape the City is an integral part of the Escape the City experience. Rest assured that we neither rent nor sell your personal information to anyone and that we will share your personal information only as described below.

  * **Escape the City Personnel:** Escape the City personnel and authorized consultants and/or contractors may have access to user information if necessary in the normal course of Escape the City business. 
  * **Business Transfers:** In some cases, we may choose to buy or sell assets. In these types of transactions, user information is typically one of the business assets that is transferred. Moreover, if Escape the City, or substantially all of its assets, were acquired, user information would be one of the assets that is transferred. 
  * **Protection of Escape the City and Others:** We may release personal information when we believe in good faith that release is necessary to comply with a law; to enforce or apply our Terms of Use and other policies; or to protect the rights, property, or safety of Escape the City, our employees, our users, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organizations for fraud protection and credit risk reduction. 
  * **User Profile information:** Information collected during registration and subsequent visits, such as your full name and location, may be displayed to other Escape the City users in your User Profile. The User Profile is the area on Escape the City where we allow you to tell other Escape the City users about yourself. You may control what personal information is displayed in your User Profile by visiting the Privacy Settings section of your User Profile. 
  * **Supporters' Activity:** Much like other online social networks, Escape the City allows non-users to browse a certain amount of your user profile (depending on your privacy settings). 
  * **Syndication:** Escape the City allows for the RSS syndication of all of its public content within the Escape the City website. 
  * **With Your Consent:** Except as noted above, we will contact you when your personal information is shared with third parties or used for a purpose incompatible with the purpose(s) for which it was originally collected, and you will be able to opt out to prevent the sharing of this information. 

We treat personal information collected through this website as confidential and will never share it unless you have expressly given us permission to do so. This website has appropriate technical and organisational security measures in place to prevent other disclosures of its members' personal information, other unauthorised or unlawful processing and accidental loss, destruction or damage. Users should be aware, however, that the Internet is by its nature not a secure medium and we cannot therefore give an absolute guarantee of security.

Our website may contain links to other websites of interest. However, once you have used these links to leave our site, you should note that we do not have any control over that other website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such sites and such sites are not governed by this privacy statement. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.

### Keeping Information Secure

  * Your Escape the City account information is protected by a password for your privacy and security. Protect against unauthorized access to your password and to your computer by logging off once you have finished using a shared computer.
  * Only employees who need personal information to perform a specific job (for example, a customer service representative) are granted access to it. All of our employees are kept up to date on our privacy and security practices.

### Ways to Control Display and Use of Your Information

  * As stated previously, you can always opt not to disclose information, but then you may be unable to use certain features on our website.
  * By visiting your User Profile, you can correct, amend, add or delete personal information on our website.
  * If you do not wish to receive e-mail from us or other Escape the City users, please visit the Notifications section of your User Profile and/or follow the instructions contained in the unwanted e-mail message.
  * However, please note that you will continue to receive all system e-mails (e.g. those regarding forgotten user passwords) and legal notices (e.g. updates to our policies) from us.
  * As explained earlier, the "help" portion of the toolbar on the majority of browsers will direct you on how to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, how to command the browser to tell you when you receive a new cookie, or how to fully disable cookies. Please note, however, that if your browser does not accept cookies, you will not be able to take advantage of some of our attractive features.
  * Users can alter or remove their data at any time through the ‘Account Settings’ page or by emailing [team@escapethecity.org](mailto:team@escapethecity.org) Users can delete their account at any time. 
  * Employers have rights of access to, and correction of, information that Escape the City holds about them, and in limited circumstances they also have rights to object to processing of information about them, under data protection law. An organisation wishing to exercise any of these rights should contact us via [team@escapethecity.org](mailto:team@escapethecity.org)

### Children Under 18 Years of Age

You must be 14 years and older to register to use the Escape the City website. As a result, Escape the City does not specifically collect information about children. If we learn that Escape the City has collected information from a child under the age of 13, we will delete that information as quickly as possible. We recommend that minors between the ages of 14 and 18 ask and receive their parents' permission before using Escape the City or sending information about themselves or anyone else over the Internet.

### Changes to this Privacy Policy

Escape the City may amend this Privacy Policy from time to time, at its sole discretion. Use of information we collect now is subject to the Privacy Policy in effect at the time such information is used. If we make changes to the Privacy Policy, we will notify you by posting an announcement on the Escape the City website so you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances if any, it is disclosed.

### Conditions of Use

If you decide to visit Escape the City website, your visit and any possible dispute over privacy is subject to this Privacy Policy and our Terms of Use, including limitations on damages, arbitration of disputes, and application of UK law.

### Effective Date of this Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy is effective as of September 1, 2012
